Sandra Lopez Guardado

15 Victoria Street | Saint James, WA | 6102 | MOBILE 0403 438 521 | EMAIL sandz.n.lopez@gmail.com

OVERVIEW

I am a strategic thinker with a strong design and communications background. I'm passionate about creative projects and optimising the user experience through authentic communications.

I have a track record of creating and implementing successful projects across social, web and print. I work hard to ensure projects meet scope, time and budget requirements, as well as relevant KPIs.

My highly developed communication and project management skills enable me to develop and maintain effective working relationships with stakeholders.

SKILLS

Campaign planning Design & brand strategy Writing & editing Visual design

Process documentation Social media content

Project & team management Stakeholder management

Teamwork User research Accessible design

Information architecture

Problem solving

Prototyping and wireframing

Responsive design Coding & Debugging

Teamwork Self-management

SOFTWARE & SYSTEMS

Adobe Indesign Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Figma Canva WordPress **Squarespace VS Code**

Command Line Git Hub HTML + CSS JavaScript **Python** React Diango

Insomnia **AutoCAD ArchiCAD** Sketchup **Twinmotion** LinkTree **Survey Monkey** Django Rest Framework Microsoft Suite

Trello Notion Slack Asana **Mail Chimp** Latergram Hootsuite Miro

EDUCATION

She Codes Plus Program

She Codes Australia (TBC April 2024)

UX Design

Google Certificate (TBC March 2024)

Digital Marketing & E-commerce

Google Certificate

Advanced Diploma of Graphic Design

North Metropolitan TAFE

Diploma of Graphic Design North Metropolitan TAFE

Cert IV, Graphic Design North Metropolitan TAFE

KEY PROJECTS Digital Design UX/UI – 'The Self Check Out' A Breast Cancer Awareness Campaign

A behaviour changing campaign that influenced the public to perform breast checks at random times during the month in line with new public health messaging. This campaign utilised established shopping habits as the first point of interaction, partnering with instore and online retailers to influence shoppers to perform a breast check when trying on clothes in change rooms or at home.

Propel Youth Arts - Drug Aware Y culture Metro Artist Exhibition

This project brought together 9 emerging local Boorloo based artists and writers to collectively respond to the theme of grounding. The exhibition showcased each artists final project and their unique take on the theme. The exhibition completed works where documented in a zine created by Sandra Lopez & Ailsa Waddell.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Graphic Designer, Sandz Studio

2021 - Present

- Oversee the management of multiple client briefs, encompassing client correspondence, invoicing, and file management.
- Cultivate strong relationships with clients to gain a comprehensive understanding of their project requirements.
- Conceptualize and implement innovative design solutions, coupled with high-level copywriting, for websites, social media platforms, and publications.
- Collaborate closely with clients to shape logo, brand, and product outcomes that exceed their expectations.
- Ensure timely and high-quality delivery of project requirements.
- Acknowledge and uphold the responsibility associated with committing to the successful delivery of project outcomes for clients.

Clerk, Perth Children's Hospital

2018 - 2023

- Provide training and onboarding for new Burns Unit clerical staff.
- Create workflow documents and clinic structure resources for clerical processes.
- Provide clerical and reception duties for the Burns Unit with a focus on customer service
- Administration and office management including ordering supplies, stationery and documents.
- Data input and processing to a high level of accuracy.

Junior Graphic Designer, Crown Perth

2021 - 2022

- Liaise with the marketing and PR teams to understand marketing briefs and desired project outcomes.
- Manage multiple projects starting new briefs while making edits to ongoing projects.
- Deliver project outcomes to industry, company and personal standards.
- Create content for internal and external comms as well overarching campaigns.
- Work collaboratively with other team members to deliver larger scale campaign roll outs.
- Liaise with external print companies to produce high quality signs, posters, vinyls, flyers, and booklets.
- Ensure all content aligns to the Crown values and integrity plan.
- Create content that adheres to corporate brand guidelines and marketing strategies.
- Use crown project management programs to keep track of project progress, stage approvals and proof edits.
- Employ industry standard design practices including document setup, project specification requirements and file saving conventions.

Media and Marketing Officer, Paper Mountain

2019 - 2021

- Create a marketing and social media engagement plan.
- Campaign rollout using Mailchimp and social media platforms.
- Liaising with artists and the gallery manager to create social media posts.
- Creating event and exhibition collateral for print and digital channels.
- Write thoughtful and high-level copy for newsletter, social media and print gallery material
- Work collaboratively with managers to organise and execute artist gallery events, workshops and exhibitions.

- Use KPI's to track marketing strategies and make changes to strategies where appropriate.
- Ensure exhibition collateral is reflective of the artist it represents.
- Ensure all collateral produced is reflective of Paper Mountain's values and principles.

Ward Clerk, Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital

2016 - 2019

Administration Assistant, Landsdale AutoCare

2014 - 2015

AWARDS

Perth Advertising and Design Club Student Skulls Award 2021

Digital Design UX/UI

'The Self Check Out' A Breast Cancer Awareness Campaign

Propel Youth Arts – Drug Aware Y culture Metro Grant Recipient 2021

Artist Exhibition – Press Flex Relax: Presented By Drug Aware

EXPERIENCE

Design and Marketing Internship 2023

Fifth Avenue Consultancy

- Assisting with and attend promotional events, presentations and functions.
- Assist with client solutions, building proposals, audience insights and promotional material.
- Create graphics for campaigns, events and clients.

Campaign and Marketing Internship 2023

Digital Loop

- Update marketing strategy including social media posting schedule.
- Create content, including copy, graphics, reels, and other visuals to post across social channels.
- Updating website, remarketing, building eDM campaigns, and other marketing material and signage.
- Assisting with and attend promotional events, presentations and functions.
- Assist with client solutions, building proposals, audience insights and promotional material.
- Preparing campaign reports and screens for clients to provide key Performance Indicator.

REFEREES

Available on request